konicaminoltaeurope.com 2018-10-19

# Privacy Policy - KONICA MINOLTA Europe

The following information provides you with details about how we process your personal data and your rights under data protection law.

## I Responsibility for data processing and company data protection officer

In line with Article 4, Paragraph 7 of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) responsibility lies with: 

**Konica Minolta Business Solutions Europe GmbH**  
Europaallee 17, 30855 Langenhagen  
Telephone: 0800-6466582  
Email: info(at)konicaminolta.de 

(See our imprint below) 

**If you have any questions about data protection, you are welcome to contact our company data protection officer at any time:**

**Dr. Frederike Rehker**  
Konica Minolta Business Solutions Deutschland GmbH  
Europaallee 17, 30855 Langenhagen  
Telephone: +49 (0)511 7404-0  
Email: dataprotection(at)konicaminolta.eu

## II Your rights

You hold the following rights with regard to your personal data processed by us:

  * access to information on the categories of the processed data, purposes of processing, recipients or categories of recipients of your data, and the planned retention period (Article 15 of the GDPR)
  * correction of inaccurate or incomplete data and/or their amendment (Article 16 of the GDPR)
  * deletion of data in line with Article 17 of the GDPR, in particular if the personal data are no longer necessary for the intended purpose or are processed illegally, or if you withdraw your consent or have lodged an objection to processing
  * restriction of data processing in line with Article 18 of the GDPR in certain circumstances insofar as, for instance, deletion is no longer possible or the deletion obligation is at issue
  * in line with Article 20 of the GDPR on data portability, to have us provide you or a third party with the personal data you supplied to us in a structured common machine-readable format
  * for reasons arising from your particular situation the right to object to data processing on account of a legitimate interest (Article 21, Paragraph 1 of the GDPR) 
  * withdrawal of your consent at any time to be effective in the future (Article 7, Paragraph 3 of the GDPR); this also of course also applies to the withdrawal of consents you granted us prior to the GDPR coming into effect
  * in line with Article 77 of the GDPR to lodge a complaint about data processing with the responsible supervisory authority

## III Collection of personal data when you visit our website

If you only our website for informational purposes, i.e. if you do not register or otherwise provide us with information, we shall only collect the personal data that your personal browser sends to our server. These data are necessary from a technical point of view to let you view our website. They are also required in order to ensure the stability and security of our website. (Legal basis is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR).

  * IP address
  * Date and time of request
  * Country of origin of request
  * Content requested (specific web page)
  * Access status/http status code
  * Website from which the request is launched
  * Browser
  * Operating system and interface
  * Browser software language and version
  * Data volume sent in each case
  * Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)

Some of the services offered on our website can only be performed if we are able to contact you. This means that availing yourself of these services is dependent on you providing us with specific personal (contact) data. We only collect, use and process these data insofar as this is necessary for the performance of the respective services. If you contact us via email or a contact form, the data you enter (your email address and other data you impart to us of your own free will, such as your name/telephone number) are stored by us so we can process your request and answer any questions you may have. We delete the data we have stored about you when it is no longer required. We restrict processing in the case of statutory retention obligations. We process your data in line with Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR.

If we request consent to process your personal data, we do so in line with Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter a of the GDPR. If processing your personal data is required to fulfil a contact or pre-contractual measures prompted by your request, our processing is legally based on Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter b of the GDPR. In cases in which processing of personal data is required to fulfil our legal obligations, processing is in line with Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter c of the GDPR. If processing of personal data is necessary to protect a legitimate interest of our company or a third party, and if at the same time the interests, basic rights and freedoms of the data subjects, which require the protection of personal data, do not take precedence over our legitimate interest, Article 6, Paragraph 1, Letter f of the GDPR shall serve as legal basis for said processing. 

Unless otherwise specified, we delete personal data in accordance with Article 17 and 18 of the GDPR or restrict their processing. We only process and store your personal data for as long as they are required to fulfil our contractual and legal obligations. Data no longer required for the intended purpose are deleted regularly unless temporary further processing is necessary, which may arise on account of other legally permissible purposes. In compliance with documentation and legal retention obligations in Germany, the necessary documents are stored for six years in line with Article 257, Paragraph 1 of the German Commercial Code (HGB) and ten years in line with Article 147, Paragraph 1 of the German Fiscal Code (AO). 

In order to avoid payment defaults, we may conduct credit checks in individual cases prior to contract closure and as part of relevant contract amendments, if we are to render services that are only billed at a later date. We protect ourselves from payment defaults by said conducting of credit checks. Based on scoring (profiling) we assess the extent to which customers will fulfil their contractual payment obligations; the score ratings help us with our decision-making. Scoring is based on a recognised mathematical-statistical method. We store the results of credit data for 365 days. 

We use cookies on our website. Cookies are small text files stored on your hard disk that are created when you use your browser to visit a website and are used by it to send specific information. Most of the cookies we use are deleted at the end of the browser session (so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain on your end device and let us recognise your browser again on your next visit (persistent cookies). Click this link for information on the cookies we use and their respective lifetimes. You can set your cookie preferences in the browser you use, and can refuse the use of cookies or restrict your refusal to the cookies of other parties, so-called third-party cookies. However your cookie preferences may result in you not being able to use all the functions offered on our Internet website. 

## V Recipients of your data

In general, we neither sell nor loan user data. We only transfer data to third parties beyond the scope of this privacy statement if it is necessary for the fulfilment of the relevant service you have requested. We work with cooperation partners to render our services. The latter perform services for you on their own responsibility/in relation to your contract with us. You can order these services and consent to the inclusion of the cooperation partner, or inclusion is based on legal permission. In the areas of Marketing, Sales, IT, Logistics and HR we also work with processors in line with Article 28 of the GDPR. These processors are carefully selected by us. We continue to bear responsibility for the protection of your data in the case of processing by a processor. In other cases we send data to government agencies at their request. However, this only takes place if a legal obligation, such as a court order, exists.

## VI Where is my data processed? 

We always process your data in Germany and European countries (EU/EEA). Insofar as your data are exceptionally processed in very limited special cases in countries outside the European Union (thus in so-called third countries), this will only take place provided you have given your express consent, it is legally envisaged, or it is necessary for us to perform our service for you. Insofar as we process data in third countries in these exceptional cases, this is performed subject to specific measures (i.e. on the basis of the existence of an adequacy decision by the EU Commission or appropriate guarantees, Article 44 et seq. of the GDPR).

## VII Targeting and Advertising

 **1\. Webanalytics:**

    **a) Use of Piwik**

This website uses Piwik, an open source software for statistical analysis of user access. Piwik uses so-called cookies or text files stored on your computer which enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this Internet website is stored on our server in Germany. This website uses Piwik with the “AnonymizeIP” function. This means that the IP address is immediately anonymised after processing and before storage, thus precluding direct linking to a particular individual. We do not consolidate Piwik data with other data we have collected. You can prevent the installation of cookies by setting your preferences in your browser software; however please note that in this case you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of this website. You can also deactivate Piwik by using [this link](https://piwik.konicaminolta.eu/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en) to store a Piwik deactivation cookie in your browser. You can find more details of the third-party provider’s privacy policy at: [piwik.org/privacy/policy](http://piwik.org/privacy/policy). The legal basis for the use of Piwik is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR. 

    **b) Use of Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called cookies or text files stored on your computer which enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. However, in the case of IP anonymisation being activated on this website, Google will first truncate your IP address within the member states of the European Union and in other countries party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. The full IP address will only be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and truncated there in exceptional cases. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website to compile reports about website activities and to perform other services related to website and Internet usage services for the website operator. The IP address transmitted by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be consolidated with other data from Google. You can prevent the storage of cookies by setting your preferences in your browser software; however please note that in this case you may not be able to make full use of all the functions of this website. You can also prevent transmission of the data generated by the cookie related to your use of the website (including your IP address) to Google and its processing of this data by downloading and installing the browser plugin available under the following link (<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>). 

This website uses Google Analytics with the “AnonymizeIP()” function. IP addresses are truncated for further processing, thus precluding any linking to a particular individual. If a personal reference is included in the data collected about you, it will therefore be excluded directly and the personal data thus deleted immediately. 

We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website and improve it on a regular basis. The statistics it yields lets us improve our product and make it more attractive to you as a user. In the exceptional cases in which personal data are transmitted to the USA, Google has submitted itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield (see <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>). 

Third-party provider information: Google Dublin, Google Ireland ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland 

For more information on terms and conditions of use and privacy go to [www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and [support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en)

The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR. 

    **c) Use of Google Adwords and remarketing**

We use Google Adwords services to draw attention to our attractive products on external websites with the help of advertising aids (so-called Google Adwords). These advertising media are delivered via so-called ad servers. Ad server cookies are used in the process to enable the evaluation of performance parameters (e.g. ad impressions, clicks or conversions). This lets us establish the extent to which individual advertising measures are successful. If you access our website via a Google ad, Google Adwords stores a cookie on your end device. This cookie stores the analysis values (unique cookie ID, number of ad impressions per placement (frequency), last impression, opt-out information (label that the user doesn’t wish to receive advertising any longer). Cookies set by Google Adwords usually expire after 30 days. They are not intended to identify you personally, but let Google Adwords recognise your Internet browser again. If you visit specific pages on the website of an Adwords customer, Google and the customer will identify that you have been forwarded to it by clicking an ad to the customer's website. As an Adwords customer, Google provides us with a statistical evaluation. Based on this evaluation we can measure the effectiveness of our advertising activities. We do not receive any further data, and in particular, we cannot identify you on the basis of the information. The legal basis for processing your data is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter a and f of the GDPR. 

The website also uses remarketing. Remarketing enables specific interest-based advertising across the Google Display Network based on previously accessed websites. Cookies are used to collect remarketing data. We and third-party providers, including Google use first-party cookies (e.g. Google Analytics cookies) in combination with third-party cookies (e.g. double click cookies) in order to orient, optimise and insert ads based on previous visits by a user to our website. Via the stored cookies, Google collects and evaluates your user behaviour when you access different websites. Konica Minolta advertising may therefore be displayed by Google or third-party providers, also on other websites. By its own admission, Google does not consolidate the data collected here with any personal data about you that may be stored by Google. In particular, Google draws attention to its use of pseudonymisation. If you do not wish to have advertising tailored to your interests displayed, you can deactivate cookies in your browser or notify Google of this for the future via the following link [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/)

For more information about privacy at Google go to: [policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) and [services.google.com/sitestats/en.html](https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html). 

The legal basis for processing your data is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter a and f of the GDPR. 

    **d) Adobe Analytics (Omniture)**

This website uses the Adobe Analytics (Omniture) web analysis service to analyse the use of our website and improve it on a regular basis. The statistics it yields lets us improve our product and make it more attractive to you as a user. In the exceptional cases in which personal data are transmitted to the USA, Adobe has submitted itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield (see <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>). 

Cookies are stored on your computer for this analysis. The information collected in this way is stored on servers, also in the USA. If you prevent the storing of cookies, please note that you may not be able to make full use of this website. You can prevent cookies being stored via your browser settings or via the “Opt-out” button at [www.adobe.com/de/privacy/opt-out.html](http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/opt-out.html). 

This website uses Adobe Analytics (Omniture) with “Before geo lookup” settings: replace visitor’s last IP octet with “0” and “Obfuscate IP-Removed”: this takes off the last octet of your IP address and replaces it with a generic IP address that cannot be tracked. Any linking to an individual is thus excluded. 

Third-party provider information: Adobe Systems Software Ireland Limited, Ireland, 4-6 Riverwalk, Citywest Business Campus, Dublin 24, Republic of Ireland; For more information about the privacy policy of the third-party provider go to: [www.adobe.com/de/privacy/policy.html](http://www.adobe.com/de/privacy/policy.html). 

The legal basis for the use of Adobe Analytics (Omniture) is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR. 

**2\. Newsletter**

Konica Minolta offers customers and interested users a newsletter. You only need to enter your email address to subscribe to the newsletter. Completion of the marked fields is voluntary, and the data is used to address you personally. Registering for the newsletter is by means of a so-called double opt-in. Once you register, we send you an email to the email address you specified asking you to confirm that you want to receive the information. If you do not confirm your registration by clicking the link in the email, the link we sent you will be deactivated and your data deleted. If you consent to its receipt, you will be given access to the following information: 

  * News and information about the Konica Minolta product portfolio
  * Exclusive invitations to events, trade fairs and webinars
  * Sending of testimonials and success stories
  * Market trends in the form of studies, market research and white papers
  * Possibility of taking part in customer satisfaction surveys

As part of the registration process we store the IP addresses you use and the dates on which you registered and confirmed registration. If you give us your consent, we will evaluate your user behaviour in relation to our websites and also the newsletter we send you and link it to your email address/user profile in our database. We also store information about the browser you use, your setting preferences in the operating system you use and information about your Internet connection which you used to access our website. The newsletter we send you provides us with your confirmation of receipt and reading, and information about the links you clicked onto in our newsletter. We also store which areas you visited on our website and in our apps. By creating a personal user profile we aim to focus our advertising on your interests and optimise the products on our website for you. 

Our newsletter contains information and news about Konica Minolta Business Solutions Europe GmbH and other affiliated group companies (Konica Minolta Business Solutions Deutschland GmbH, Konica Minolta IT Solutions GmbH, Konica Minolta Business Solutions Austria GmbH, Konica Minolta Business Solutions (Belgium) N.V., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Nederland B.V., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Spain S.A., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Italia S.p.A., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Portugal, Unipessoal Lda., NEA RENT - ALUGUER E COMÉRCIO DE EQUIPAMENTOS S.A., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Sweden AB, Konica Minolta Business Solutions Denmark A/S, Business Center Nord og Midtsjælland A/S, Konica Minolta Business Solutions Finland Oy, Konica Minolta Business Solutions Norway AS, Konica Minolta Business Solutions Czech spol. s r.o., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Bulgaria EOOD, WEBCOM a.s., WEBCOM Poland Sp. z o.o., Konica Minolta Hungary Business Solutions Ltd., Konica Minolta Business Solutions SE Ltd, Konica Minolta Croatia - business solutions, Ltd, Konica Minolta Poslovna Rjesenja BH d.o.o., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Polska Sp.z o.o., Konica Minolta Slovakia spol. s r.o., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Romania s.r.l., Konica Minolta Business Solutions Slovenija, poslovne resitve, d.o.o., Konica Minolta Baltia, UAB, Konica Minolta Business Solutions Greece S.A., Minolta (UK) Limited, Konica Minolta Marketing Services Limited, Konica Minolta Marketing Services Ireland Limited, Konica Minolta Marketing Services B.V., Charterhouse Print Management AG, Charterhouse AB, Indicia Group Limited, Hamsard 3099 Limited, Evolving Media Limited, Indicia Limited, Indicia Edinburgh Limited, Konica Minolta Business Solutions France S.A.S., Conibi S.A.S, Dactyl Buro du Centre S.A.S., OMR Impressions S.A.S., Serians S.A.S., Konica Minolta Business Solutions (UK) Ltd., Konica Minolta Business Solutions East Ltd., KONICA MINOLTA Business Solutions (Northern Scotland) Ltd, Capture Imaging Ltd, ProcessFlows Holdings Ltd, ProcessFlows (UK) Ltd, Software Paradise Ltd, Digital Document Solutions Ltd, Konica Minolta Business Solutions (Ideal) Ltd., Konica Minolta Printing Solutions (UK) Ltd., Konica Minolta Business Solutions (Wales) Ltd., Konica Minolta Sensing Europe B.V., Mobotix AG). 

You can unsubscribe to the newsletter at any time. You can also send an email to unsubscription(at)konicaminolta.eu or use the contact data in the site notice. 

We process your data in line with Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter a of the GDPR. 

**Use of Marketo**

We use Marketo both in the course of newsletter registration and to send you information. Marketo helps us to collect data about how you use our website and communication activities to optimise our services/products accordingly and conduct email marketing and sales activities. Processing is partially automated with the aim of assessing specific personal aspects (profiling). Marketo captures your IP address and uses cookies (text files stored on your computer – see above) to track and analyse website use in order to tailor information to suit the interests of the user. Information generated by the cookies is transmitted to a Marketo server (sited in the EU/EEA) and stored there. On our behalf, Marketo uses this information to evaluate website use by registered persons and to compile reports about website activities. You can prevent cookies being stored via the setting preferences in your browser software. However, your cookie preferences may result in you not being able to use all the online functions offered on our website. In exceptional unforeseen cases in which personal data are transmitted to the USA, Marketo has submitted itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield (see <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>). We have also concluded an agreement with Marekto about the GDPR. 

Third-party provider information: Marketo Inc., 901 Mariners Island Blvd. Suite 500, San Mateo, CA 94404, USA; you can find the Marketo data privacy statement under the following URL: [documents.marketo.com/legal/privacy/](https://documents.marketo.com/legal/privacy/)

The legal basis for the use of Marketo is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR.

## VIII YouTube

YouTube videos are included on our websites. They are stored on [www.Youtube.com](http://www.youtube.com/), but can be played back directly on our website. On including videos on our website we activated advanced data protection mode. This means that if you do not play back videos, no data about you is transmitted to YouTube. However, if you play back videos, the data are sent to YouTube. Initially, YouTube receives the information that you have accessed the corresponding page on our website. Other data can also be transmitted to YouTube, of which we have no knowledge. In this case also, we have no influence on data transmission. If you log into YouTube the transmitted data are directly linked to your account. If you do not wish this to happen, you have to log out of YouTube before you play back videos on our websites. YouTube stores your data as a user profile and uses them for advertising and market research purposes and/or to tailor its website to user needs. Evaluation of this nature may in particular be used for targeted advertising (even in the case of users who have not logged in). YouTube offers you a right of objection to the creation to user profiles, which you must lodge directly with YouTube. 

The YouTube privacy statement provides more information on the purpose and scope of data acquisition and processing, and also additional information on your rights and settings options to protect your privacy: [www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy](https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy). Google also processes your personal data in the USA and has subjected itself to the EU-US Privacy Shield <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>. 

The legal basis for the inclusion of YouTube videos is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f of the GDPR.

## IX Privacy Policy for Job Applicants

 **1\. Scope and purposes of data processing**

    **a) Internal data processing when we review your application**

As part of the application process, we process the specified data for the purpose of reviewing your application and suitability for the vacant post. We store your data only in our own data centre in Germany. We may deploy specialised service providers to review your application. Suitable applications for a job are forwarded by HR to the relevant department or country subsidiary for detailed reviewing. You must supply your curriculum vitae, references or appropriate credentials to let us fully assess your application. When entering your details, please note the following mandatory fields: Last name, first name, email address, postal address, salary expectations, period of notice in present position. In addition, you must attach at least one enclosure. Other details, including a photo, are optional. 

Our job portal also offers you the following options:

  * Application: you can find an overview of your applications to Konica Minolta here. You can view the details by clicking on the individual applications. If we have requested you via email to supply missing documents, you can upload them here. You also have the option of withdrawing your application.
  * Dates: As soon as we suggest a date via email, you will be able to view it in the "Dates" area and confirm or reject it. If you are unable to attend on a suggested date, we will send you a new date.
  * Profile: you can update your personal data at any time under "Profile". Changes are forwarded to us automatically.

We delete your application data five months after the end of the application process in line with Article 61b, Paragraph 1 of the German Labour Courts Act (ArbGG) and Article 15 of the German General Act on Equal Treatment (AGG). The application process ends once a final status has been set for the respective application (Rejection | Acceptance | Talent pool). Data processing is performed on the basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter b of the GDPR, Article 26 of the new German Data Protection Act (BDSG-neu). 

If you are under the age of 18, we require the consent of your legal guardians in order to conclude a contract with you. 

    **b) Group job portal**

We store your application data in our job portal. Konica Minolta Business Solutions Deutschland GmbH and Konica Minolta Business Solutions Europe GmbH have access to this portal. 

This enables us to match your qualification profile with other vacancies and draw your attention to other suitable posts. Access can be particularly useful if you have applied for a post that is also vacant in the same or similar form in one of the aforementioned companies, or if you live in a border region. If you have applied for an international post, the respective countries may be involved in the selection process. However, if you do not wish it, you can object to said access at any time. Please apply to the point of contact specified in the vacancy posting in order to exercise your right of objection. An objection, regardless of the time you file it, has no influence on the selection process for your current application. Data processing is performed on the legal basis of Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter f or – if you have explicitly applied for an international post – Letter b of the GDPR, Article 26 of the new German Data Protection Act (BDSG-neu). Your rights are protected by internal contractual provisions which ensure a high standard of data privacy. 

    **c) Storage of your application in our talent pool**

If we are unable to consider your application for a specific post, in some cases however we would like to store your application in our talent pool. We will send you a separate invitation to join this talent pool, which you can accept or reject via our system. We can thus contact you if a suitable vacancy comes up for you. We will only store your application if you have given us your express consent to do so. 

If you consent, we will store your application data for a maximum period of twelve months, after which they are automatically deleted. Please note that in the case of your objection to data processing, we will no longer be able to consider you when filling future posts that may be suitable for you. The legal basis in this instance is Article 6, Paragraph 1, Sentence 1, Letter a of the GDPR. 

**2\. Applications from apprentices, students and school-goers seeking work placements**

We will be happy to accept your application as an apprentice, student or school-goer seeking a work placement. We also treat these applications according to the aforementioned principles.
